shlonline.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how SHL Group Limited collects, uses and safeguards personal information that you may provide to us. When we refer to personal information we mean information or an opinion about you, from which your identity is apparent or can be reasonably ascertained.

We are committed to promoting confidence in the manner in which your personal information is handled by us. In this regard, we will act ethically and as evidence of this commitment, we will comply with the privacy and data protection requirements of the countries in which we operate.

**Contents:**

  * Collection of personal data
  * Use and disclosure
  * Cookies and automatic data collection
  * Log files
  * Security
  * Protection of children's information
  * Access to personal information we hold about you
  * Your right to challenge
  * Privacy compliance
  * Complaints resolution
  * Changes to this statement
  * Collection of personal data

In general, you can visit SHL websites without telling us who you are and without revealing any information about yourself. However there may be occasions when you choose to give us personal information. Generally this will be for the purposes of:

  * receiving further information from us;
  * for recruitment, selection and development purposes by potential employers, managing recruitment and human resource processes and any related purpose where you have consented to the collection.

We do not collect information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations. We do not collect or use personal data for any purpose other than those indicated above and will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you. If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, we offer you the means to consent to this new purpose by indicating in a box at the point on the site where personal data is collected.

**Use and disclosure**

If we require you to provide certain personal information about yourself for the purposes described above, we will not rent, sell or exchange information about you to third parties except to your employers or potential employers, where you consent, where you would reasonably expect the information to be disclosed or where we are legally required to disclose such information

**Cookies and automatic data collection**

We may automatically log personal data or link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals. However, we will only use this information to help us respond to queries you may have about our products or services or to tell you about other SHL products and services that we think you may be interested in. We will not pass this information on to any third parties.

The Internet browser that you use may make use of a feature called a "cookie" to assign identification to your computer. We do not use cookies to store personal data or to link personal data to non-personal data, unless you have first agreed to this by selecting the "Remember Me" option. If you select this option, a cookie will be placed on your computer which will allow our website [online.shl.com](http://online.shl.com/) to recognise you when you return to our website. No personal information will be stored in this cookie.

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance.

The following table describes the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete SHL cookies having visited the site.

_Persistent Cookies for Site Analytics and Performance_

**Cookie name** | **Purpose**  
---|---  
  
_Google (Analytics)_

__utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz_

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

More information: [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)  
  
_AddThis_  
| 

AddThis helps us to integrate social media sharing tools into our website such as facebook or twitter and to measure the effectiveness of these sharing tools.

More information: [AddThis opt-out](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out#.UHRbwRXA-So)  
  
_SHL Online local storage_

_localstorage-journal_

| Remembers products you add to your basket. Helps control access and controls where you are in the process. Used to remember your email address to speed up sign-in next time you visit the site (but only if you tick 'Remember Me').  
  
_External web services_ : We use a number of external web services on the SHL site, mostly to display content within our web pages. For example, to display slideshows we sometimes use SlideShare; to show videos we use YouTube. This is not an exhaustive or complete list of the services we use, or might use in the future, when embedding content, but these are the most common. As with the social buttons we cannot prevent these sites, or external domains, from collecting information on your usage of this embedded content. If you are not logged in to these external services then they will not know who you are but are likely to gather anonymous usage information e.g. number of views, plays, loads etc.

_Email tracking_ : Some emails we can track, at an individual level, whether the user has opened and clicked on the email. We rarely use the latter information at a personal level, rather we use it to understand open and click rates on our emails to try and improve them. Sometimes we do use the personal information e.g. to re-email people who didn’t click the first time. If you want to be sure that none of your email activity is tracked then you should opt out of SHL’s emails which you can do via unsubscribe option in the footer of emails we send.

**Log Files**

Like most web site providers, we analyse server log files to collect statistical information about how our web sites are used. This type of information is collected only at an aggregate level and includes browser types, Internet service providers, referring/exit pages, platform types, date/time stamps and other broad demographic data. Such data is not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Security**

We protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information and we have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to do so. SHL operates its own Internet Data Centre that is designed to keep mission critical human resource services and data online and secure at all times. We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:

  * Unauthorized access
  * Improper use or disclosure
  * Unauthorised modification
  * Unlawful destruction or accidental loss
  * All our employees and data processors, who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data, are required to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data.

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation.

**Protection of children's information**

The SHL web sites do not publish content or collect data that is targeted at children.

**Access to personal information we hold about you**

You can ask us whether we are keeping personal data about you.

**Making a request**

Requests may be made in writing to:

Ref: PVCSHL  
Data Protection officer  
SHL Group Limited  
The Pavillion  
1 Atwell Place  
Thames Ditton  
Surrey, KT7 0NE  
UK

Requests can be submitted to the above address by printing and completing a [Subject Access Request Form ](http://www.shl.com/assets/SHL_Subject_Access_Request_Form.pdf)(8KB PDF). The purpose of this form is to ensure that you give us all the necessary information to enable us to comply with your request. You do not have to use this form, but if you do not you should ensure that all the required information on this form is provided.

Note: The period of 40 days in which the organisation must respond to the request will not commence until we have received written proof of your identity. Requests can not be made by telephone or any other means.

**Proof of Identity**

Regardless of the original means of request (letter or email), SHL will require proof of identity before releasing personal data. This may be provided in the following forms:

\- A paper copy of a bank statement, utility bill or other company letter sent to you, or;  
\- Apaper copy of your driving license, birth certificate, passport or benefits book.

Proof of identity should be signed and dated by you and sent to the address above with a stamped addressed envelope so that we can send the information that you have requested to you.

**What we will send you**

You will be sent a paper notification of:

  * Whether SHL is processing personal data about you.
  * A description of the data and the purposes of processing the data. (SHL does not disclose personal data to 3rd parties so this information will not be included).
  * An explanation of any codes or abbreviations used so as to make the notification intelligible.
  * If we can, information as to the sources of the data.

You may request that the above information is sent to you by email instead.

**Fees**

We reserve the right to charge a £10 administration fee for providing this information to you.

**Period for Responding**

Your request will be dealt with:

  * Within forty days of receipt of the request; or if later
  * Within forty days of receiving the fee and the information needed to verify your identity and locate the information that you seek.

**Your right to challenge**

If at any time you wish to change personal information that is incorrect or wish to have your personal information deleted, please contact us in writing via the address below. Unless personal information is required to be retained by us for administrative or legal reasons, SHL will meet such requests at the earliest possible opportunity by deleting or amending your personal information where appropriate.

**Privacy compliance**

SHL Group (and in particular, its US subsidiaries SHL USA Inc and Previsor Inc) comply with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. SHL USA Inc and Previsor Inc have certified that they adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view SHL USA Inc and Previsor Inc’s certification, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>

**Complaints resolution**

We are committed to providing a fair and responsive system for handling and resolving complaints concerning the handling of personal information. You have a right to complain and to have your complaint handled efficiently if you are concerned about our handling of your personal information. We believe that any complaint that we may receive is a valuable opportunity to improve the services that we deliver to you and to maintain your confidence in our services.

If at any time you wish to lodge a complaint in respect of the handling, use or disclosure of your personal information by us, you may do so by contacting our Privacy Officer at the address below.

We aim to investigate and advise you of the outcome of the complaint promptly. If you are not satisfied with our handling of your complaint, you may contact your local data protection registrar.

**Changes to this statement**

SHL will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of this privacy statement and post notification of change on web site home pages or other places we deem appropriate. Questions regarding this statement should be directed in writing to:  

Ref: PVCSHL  
Data Protection officer  
SHL Group Limited  
The Pavillion  
1 Atwell Place  
Thames Ditton  
Surrey, KT7 0NE  
UK
